Phoebe found out about this lady...
我們跑去海邊 因為菲比找到一個女人
...who knew her parents, and I don't know what happened.
她認識她的父母 然後我就不知道了
I'm your mother.
我是你的母親
Monica joked she wouldn't date Chandler.
摩妮卡開玩笑說 她不會跟錢德這種人約會
I don't know what happened there either.
他一直很在意 然後我也不知道了
Ross' new girlfriend shows up.
羅斯的新女朋友邦妮跑來
Rachel gets Bonnie to shave her head. Then they kiss.
瑞秋說服她理了個大光頭 然後羅斯和瑞秋接吻了
Now he has to choose Rachel or the bald girl.
現在他得在瑞秋 和光頭女之間二選一
I don't know what happened there either.
然後我還是不知道
Hold on. Let me go get Chandler.
等一下，我去找錢德來
She's helping me. My head's sunburned.
她在幫我搽藥，我的頭曬傷了
-Thanks a million. -You're welcome a million.
感激不盡 不用客氣
Smell it.
你聞
Minty.
涼涼的
I'll be in our room.
我先回房去
Oh,my God!
天哪
I know.
我知道
I got to go.
好，我走了
Why?
什麼？為什麼？
I got to go break up with Bonnie.
我得跟邦妮分手
Here? Now?
在這裡？現在？
I can't stay here all night.
我不能整晚留在這裡
If I go in there,she'll want to...
要是我回房，她會想…
...do stuff.
嘿咻
Can't you say you aren't in the mood?
你不能說你沒心情嗎？
No,she likes that.
她喜歡那樣
Faking sleep doesn't work.
裝睡也沒用
I've woken up many times with her
我經常早上醒來發現她在…
好
-Why am I telling you? -I don't know.
我說這個幹什麼？ 我不知道
-Not every morning -Making it worse!
並不是每天早上都… 再描會更黑
The One with the Jellyfish
本集播出：「前緣難續」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
You probably want to know how it happened.
你大概想知道前因後果
I think I can figure it out.
我猜想得到
I was born,and then everyone lied their asses off.
我出生之後 大家開始卯起來撒謊
No,it wasn't like that.
不是那樣的
Remember how I said Lilly,Frank and I were close?
我不是說過 莉莉、法蘭克和我很要好？
We were very close.
我們非常要好
How close?
怎麼說？
The three of us were kind of a couple.
我們三個是一對
I don't know how that would work.
三個怎麼會是一對
I'm not asking!
我們… 我不是在問你
Anyhow,somehow I got pregnant...
總之，我不知怎的懷孕了
...and I was...
我很…
...scared. I was stupid and selfish....
…害怕，我愚昧又自私…
I was 18 years old. Remember what it was like to be 18?
我才18歲 還記得你的18歲嗎？
Mom killed herself and my dad ran off.
記得，媽自殺，爸跑掉
I lived in a Gremlin with a guy who talked to his hand.
我跟一個叫山迪的人住在一起 他會跟他的手說話
I'm sorry. I thought I'd left you with the best parents.
對不起 我以為他們是世上最好的父母
I didn't hear about them till a few years ago.
直到幾年前 我才聽說他們的事
By then,you were already grown-up.
當時你已經長大了
You're here and I would really like to get to know you.
既然你來了，我也想多認識你
Well,everybody does.
每個人都想認識我
I'm a really cool person.
我是個很酷的人
You had 29 years to find out, but you didn't even try.
你有29年的時間可以查 卻連試都沒試
You walked out on me, and I'll do the same.
你扔下我不管，現在我也要
I don't ever want to see you again.
等一下
我不想再見到你
Where's my purse?
我的皮包呢？
Shoot! We're out of soda.
討厭，沒有汽水了
-I'll get you some. -Really?
我去幫你買 真的？
No,because I'm not your boyfriend.
才怪，我又不是你的男朋友
Hey,Pheebs,how'd it go?
菲比，怎麼樣？
My mom's friend,Phoebe, is actually my birth mom.
我媽的朋友菲比 其實是我的親生母親
I found a dried-up seahorse.
我檢到一個幹掉的海馬
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
My new mom, who's a big fat abandoner.
我的新媽媽當年拋棄了我
Don't you want to stay here and talk about it?
菲比，等等 你不坐下來聊一聊嗎？
I need to be alone.
不了，我想靜一靜
摩妮卡
Man. Hey...
...what if you found out that your mom wasn't really your mom...
要是你發現你媽不是你媽
...and your new mom turned out to be really hot?
而你的新媽媽又很辣呢？
Oh,man,huh?
But,it's your mom.
但她是你媽耶
No,I'm talking about your mom.
不，我是在說你媽
It's over.
結束了
Was it awful?
很慘嗎？
It was long.
很久
I didn't realize how late it was...
我沒意識到那麼晚了
...till I saw the five o'clock shadow on her head.
直到她頭上出現5點鐘的日影
She didn't want to stay. I called a cab. She just left.
她不想留下來 我幫她叫了車，她剛走
I wrote you a letter.
我寫了封信給你
Oh,thank you!
謝謝
I like mail.
我喜歡收信
It's just some things I've been thinking about. About us.
我想了一些關於我們的事
Before we even think about us getting back together...
在我們考慮復合之前
...I need to know how you feel about this stuff.
我得知道你對這封信的想法
好
It's 5:30 in the morning.
現在是早上5點半
So I'd better get cracking on this baby.
我最好趕快看完
I'll be waiting for you. Come up when you're done.
我等你，看完就上來
I'll be up...
好，我要花…
...in 18 pages.
十八頁的時間
Front and back.
從頭到尾
Very exciting!
好興奮喔
What happened to you? Why didn't you come up?
怎麼了？你怎麼沒上來？
Done.
看完了
-You just finished? -I wanted to be thorough.
你才剛看完？ 我想看仔細一點
This is clearly very important to you. To us.
這對你…對我們顯然很重要
I wanted to read every word carefully.
我想一字一句用心斟酌
Twice.
斟酌兩次
Does it?
所以…行嗎？
I'm sorry?
什麼？
Does it?
行嗎？
Does it? Does it?
行嗎？行嗎？
I wanted to give that whole "Does it?" part another glance.
我想再瞄一眼「行嗎」的部份
What do you mean? You said you read it twice.
什麼意思？你說你看了兩次
It either does or doesn't. If you have to think
行不行一句話 如果你還要考慮…
No,I don't have to think about it.
不，我不用考慮，不用
In fact...
事實上…
...I've decided. I have decided...
我已經決定了，我決定…
...that it...
這件事…
...does.
行
-Are you sure? -Sure,I'm sure!
你確定？ 確定
There's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on earth.
好，發生核爆災難 我是世上僅存的男人
Would you go out with me?
你會跟我約會嗎？
I've got canned goods.
我有罐頭喔
Take a look at this!
喂，你們看
Check this baby out! Dug me a hole.
你們瞧瞧，我挖了個洞
Excellent hole,Joe.
好棒的洞啊
Oh,no! My hole!
不！我的洞！
My foot!
我的腳！
What is it?
怎麼了？
Jellyfish sting! It hurts!
我被水母咬了，好痛…
Can we help you to the house?
要不要扶你回去？
It's two miles.
2哩耶
And I'm tired from digging.
而且我挖洞挖得好累
Damn the jellyfish!
該死的水母
Damn all the jellyfish!
所有的水母都去死
Do something.
得想個辦法
There's only one thing.
只有一個辦法
What is it?
什麼辦法？
Pee on it.
在傷口上撒尿
Gross!
什麼？好惡！
I saw it on Discovery Channel.
別怪我 我是在探索頻道上看到的
He's right. There's ammonia in that...
他沒唬你，尿液裡有氨
...that kills the pain.
可以止痛
Forget it. It doesn't hurt that bad!
我不要，其實沒那麼痛…
You can use my hole for privacy.
你可以躲進我的洞裡
I'm ready to get the hell out of here.
我準備好要走了
Are you?
你們…？真的？
That's so great!
太棒了
Not for Bonnie.
邦妮好可憐
But for you,yea!
但恭喜你們了
-How was the beach? -Nothing. I don't know.
海邊好玩嗎？ 不怎麼樣，我不知道
-What happened? -Nothing.
怎麼了？ 沒事
-I'm going to shower. -Me too.
我要去沖澡 我也是
Me too.
我也是
I'll put this in the car.
我把袋子拿到車上
I have to go pack!
我得去收東西
-And it really does? -lt does.
真的行嗎？ 行
It really and truly does.
真的真的行
It so does not!
行你個頭！
（中央咖啡館）
She wants me to take responsibility for everything that went wrong.
她要我對我們的失和 負起全部的責任
She goes on for five pages about how I was unfaithful to her.
她寫了整整五頁 說我如何不忠
We were on a break!
我們當時分手了
If you say that one more time, I'll break up with you.
天哪，你再說一次 我就跟你分手
This breakup was not all my fault. She says here...
分手不是我一個人的錯 她寫說
..."lf you accept full responsibility...
「要是你負起全部的責任」
...I can begin to trust you again.
「我就能再次信任你」
Does that seem like something you can do? Does it?"
「你想你辦得到嗎？行嗎？」
不行
You have what you want. You're back with her.
你得償所願，跟她復合了
If you bring this up now, you'll wreck it.
現在提出來 會毀了你一生中最美好的事
Yeah,I know. You're right.
我知道，你說得對
I'll let it go.
我會就此打住
But you know how hard it is to forget this?
但你們瞭解這件事很難忘記吧
Sure,it's hard...
當然很難
...but you don't have to talk about it.
但你不必拿出來談
A lot happened on that trip...
這次度假有很多事
...that we should never,ever talk about.
都該從此絕口不提
What happened on that beach?
在海邊到底怎麼了？
It's between us and the sea,Ross.
那是我們和大海的秘密
Hi,Ursula.
烏蘇拉
I know that we haven't talked in a long time.
我知道我們很久沒聯絡了
Our mom is not our birth mom. This other lady is our birth mom.
但我們的媽媽不是親媽媽 另一個女的才是
Right,the one that lives in Montauk.
對，住在莫陶克的那個
You know her?
你認識她？
No. I read about her in Mom's suicide note.
不認識，但媽的遺書裡有提到
There was a suicide note? Do you still have it?
媽有留遺書？還在嗎？
Hang on.
等一下
I can't believe you didn't tell me there was a suicide note.
你居然沒告訴我有遺書
Yeah,so how have you been doing?
是啊，你最近好嗎？
Shut up!
我…閉嘴
"Goodbye,Phoebe and Ursula. I'll miss you.
「別了，菲比與烏蘇拉」 「我會想念你們」
P.S. Your mom lives in Montauk."
「又：你們母親住在莫陶克」
You just wrote this!
這是你剛才寫的
It's pretty much the gist.
差不多是這個意思
Except for the poem. You read the poem,right?
只差那首詩，你讀過那首詩吧
沒有
All right. Hang on.
等一下
Pass the cheese,please.
請把起司給我
You can't even look at me,can you?
你連看都不敢看我，對吧？
對
It's Phoebe! We can talk to Phoebe!
是菲比！我們可以跟菲比說話
I'm too depressed to talk.
我很沮喪，不想說話
I'll give you $1000 to talk to us.
我給你1千元開口費
What about making that beach trip an annual thing?
我們要不要每年都回去玩？
不要
What happened out there?
夠了，到底出了什麼事？
What? We took a walk. Nothing happened.
什麼？ 我們只是去散步，沒什麼
I came back with nothing all over me.
我身上什麼都沒沾到
What happened? Joey?
拜託，到底是…喬伊？
All right.
好吧 不行
We swore we'd never tell.
我們發誓要死守秘密
They'll never understand.
他們不會瞭解的
We have to get it out. It's eating me alive!
我們得說出來，我快被逼瘋了
-Monica got stung by a jellyfish. -All right!
摩妮卡被水母咬到 好吧
好吧
I got stung.
我被咬到
Stung bad.
咬得很嚴重
I couldn't stand.
站都站不直
I couldn't walk.
走也走不動
We were two miles from the house.
我們離小屋2哩遠
We were scared and alone.
既孤單又害怕
We didn't think we could make it.
我們還以為死定了
I was in too much pain.
我痛得要命
And I was tired from digging.
我剛挖完洞好累
Then Joey remembered something.
然後喬伊想起一件事
I'd seen it on Discovery Channel.
是在探索頻道上看到的
Wait,I saw that.
慢著，我也看過
On the Discovery Channel. About jellyfish and how if you
是探索頻道沒錯 它說要是你被水母…
You peed on yourself?
你在自己身上撒尿？
You can't say that! You don't know!
你不能這麼說！你不知道
I thought I would pass out.
我都快痛昏了
I tried,but I couldn't...
我試過，但沒辦法…
...bend that way.
彎成那個姿勢
所以…
That's right. I stepped up.
沒錯，我挺身而出
She's my friend and she needed help.
她是我的朋友，她需要幫助
If I had to, I'd pee on any of you.
如果有必要 我也會在你們身上撒尿
Only...
只不過…
...I couldn't.
我尿不出來
I got the stage fright.
我怯場了
I wanted to help, but there was too much pressure.
我很想幫忙，但壓力太大了
So I turned to Chandler.
所以我找錢德
Joey kept screaming at me, "Do it now. Do it. Do it now!"
喬伊一直對我大叫 「快尿！快點尿！」
Sometimes,late at night, I can still hear the screaming.
有時在深夜裡 我還會聽到那個叫聲
Because I do it through my wall to freak you out.
那是我在隔壁嚇你
Maybe there's somebody you guys could talk to.
也許你們可以找人談談
Oh,who?
找誰？
It's not like they have a group for people like us.
難道這種事還有團體治療？
Yeah,no,there's this guy Owen,he's the best.
有個叫歐文的很厲害
Might have his card.
我有他的名片
And fuchsia and mauve
還有紫紅色和淡紫色
Those are the 66 colors of my bedroom
這就是我房裡的六十六種顏色
I invite all of you to count the colors in your bedroom.
大家都回去算算房裡的顏色吧
Except for you. You go away.
你除外，你給我滾
I'll go in a second.
我馬上就走
I just want to tell you...
我只想告訴你
...there wasn't a day I didn't regret giving you up.
我每天都在後悔把你送人
Okay,bye.
好，再見
I'm not done.
我還沒說完
The reason I never looked you up was because...
我之所以沒找過你是因為…
...I was afraid you'd react...
我很怕你的反應
...just like the way you're reacting now.
會跟現在一樣
Can't we just start from here? Please?
我們不能從現在開始嗎？
No.
不行
好吧
Sorry.
抱歉
One last thing.
最後一件事
You came looking for family.
你來找你的家人
I'm family.
我就是了
I'm it.
沒別人了
Now I'm done.
我說完了
It's not like we're losing anything.
我們又沒什麼損失
I guess you're right.
你說得對
It's not like we know each other or have anything in common.
我們又不熟 也沒什麼共同點
I don't know. It's not like...
我不曉得，我們不見得…
...we don't have anything in common.
沒有共同點
I mean,I like pizza.
像我喜歡披薩
I like pizza!
我也喜歡披薩
Wait,I like the Beatles.
是嗎？等等，我喜歡披頭四
Oh,my God! So do l.
天哪，我也是
Puppies. Cute or ugly?
等等，小狗狗可不可愛？
So cute!
可愛死了
You see?
看吧
But I'm still mad at you.
但我還是很氣你
I know.
我知道
I'm mad at me too.
我也很氣自己
Do you want to get something to eat? I'm kind of hungry.
你想吃東西嗎？我有點餓
Hey! Me too!
我也是
Uncanny.
太不可思議了
It looks like rain and I don't have my umbrella.
好像快下雨了，我沒帶傘
Me neither. I really hate that.
我也是，真討厭
Stop it. Now you're just doing it to freak me out.
夠了，你現在只是想嚇我
I missed you.
我好想你
I missed you too.
我也很想你
I was so nervous about that letter.
我對那封信好緊張
But the way you owned up to everything...
但是你這麼坦然認錯
...it just showed me how much you've grown.
證明你真的成長不少
I suppose.
大概吧
You have,Ross. You should give yourself credit.
你有，羅斯，你不該妄自菲薄
My mom never thought this would work out.
我媽一直覺得我們無法復合
She said,"Once a cheater, always a cheater."
她說：出軌是不可原諒的
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
真希望沒有這4個月的空白
But if time was what you needed to gain a little perspective....
但要是時間能讓你看清楚一點
We were on a break!
我們當時分手了！
-Coffeehouse? -You bet.
喝咖啡？ 好
It took two people to break up this relationship.
這段感情會破裂是兩個人的錯
You and that girl, which yesterday you took full responsibility for.
對，你和影印店那個女的 你昨天表明願意負責
I didn't know what I took responsibility for.
我不知道我負的是什麼責
I didn't finish the letter.
我沒把信看完 什麼？
I fell asleep.
我睡著了
You fell asleep?
你睡著了？
It was 5:30 in the morning.
當時是早上5點半
And you had rambled on for 18 pages.
你一廢話就廢話了十八頁
Front and back!
從頭到尾
By the way,Y-O-U-apostrophe-R-E means "you are."
還有 「you're」是指「you are」
Y-O-U-R means "your."
「Y-O-U-R」是代表your
I can't believe I thought of getting back with you! We are so over.
我居然會想跟你復合 我們根本就完了
Fine by me!
無所謂
Those spelling tips will be handy Saturday nights at home...
你星期六晚上 跟摩妮卡玩拼字遊戲時
...playing Scrabble with Monica.
一定不會寫錯字
Sorry!
對不起
All that sleep you'll miss wishing you were with me!
我只可憐你會想我想到失眠
Don't worry about me falling asleep.
別怕我會睡不著
I still have your letter!
我還有你的信
Just so you know, it's not that common.
順便告訴你 這種事並不常見
It doesn't happen to every guy.
並非男人都會這樣
And it is a big deal!
這是很嚴重的
I knew it!
我就知道
Gin.
我贏了
We were playing gin?
我們在玩金羅美牌？
If we were a couple, we could play naked.
如果我們是一對，就可以光著身體玩了
-Would you stop? -Okay. All right.
別再說了 好吧
All right.
好啦
I think you're great.
我覺得你很棒
I think you're sweet and smart...
我覺得你人很好，很聰明
...and I love you.
我愛你
But you'll always be the guy who peed on me.
但你永遠是在我身上撒尿的人